David E. Lilienthal Papers, 1900-1981 (bulk 1950-1981 ): Inventory MC148
EADs for public policy collection from import batch
David E. Lilienthal Papers
1900-1981
1950-1981
EADs for public policy collection from import batch
MC148
632 boxes
4 items
David Lilienthal served on the Wisconsin Public Service Commission (1923-1932), as a member of the board of directors (1933-1941) and then chairman (1941-1946) of the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), as first chairman (1946-1950) of the Atomic Energy Commission, and, later, in private business as an industrial consultant and chairman (1955) of the Development and Resources Corporation, which was involved with the Khuzestan Program in Iran. This collection consists of the papers of Lilienthal spanning his entire career, including correspondence, reports, articles, speeches, and printed matter.
Biographical / Historical
1931 Wisconsin Railroad Commission
1931-1932 Wisconsin Public Service Commission, Member Commissioner
1933-1946 Tennessee Valley Authority Member, Board of Directors, 1933-1940 Director and Chairman, 1941-1946
1946 United States Department of State, Board of Consultants on the International Control of Atomic Energy, Chairman
1946-1950 U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Chairman
Publications by Lilienthal: TVA, Democray on the March (New York: Harper & Brothers, 1944), This I Do Believe (New York: Harper, 1949), Big Business, A New Era (New York: Harper, 1953), Change, Hope, and the Bomb (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1963), The Journals of David E. Lilienthal, vols. I-VII. (New York: Harper, 1964-1983), and Atomic Energy, A New Start (New York: Harper & Row, 1980)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the papers of Lilienthal spanning his entire career. Included are correspondence, reports, articles, speeches, and printed matter relating to his positions with the Wisconsin Public Service Commission (1923-1932), as a member of the board of directors (1933-1941) and then chairman (1941-1946) of the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), as first chairman (1946-1950) of the Atomic Energy Commission, and, later, in private business as an industrial consultant and chairman (1955) of the Development and Resources Corporation, which was involved with the Khuzestan Program in Iran. Also present are manuscripts for six works, including TVA, Democracy on the March (1944), Big Business, A New Era (1953), Atomic Energy, A New Start (1980), and the published Journals of David E. Lilienthal, Vols. I-VII, 1939-1981 (1964-1983), as well as his personal, unpublished, manuscript journals (1915-1981).
Other personal papers include documents, early correspondence (1917-1923) with his future wife, Helen Lamb, and other family members, appointment books, scrapbooks, film and tape recordings, photographs, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection may have been put in this order by Lilienthal or his administrative staff before transfer to Princeton, and further arrangement may have been done by an archivist at Princeton but no information is available regarding the extent to which an archivist was involved in the current arrangement. In 2019 a number of materials after series 22 were rehoused and merged with corresponding series into series 8, 10-13, and 25. Other series that are are broken up in in two, including speeches and correspondence, are left intact.
Conditions Governing Access
LINKED DIGITAL CONTENT NOTE: Please note that some previously linked digital content is temporarily unavailable while the data is being migrated from an outdated access service. If you would like to access this content, please send a request to mudd@princeton.libanswers.com.
Collection is open for research use.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access to audiovisual material in this collection follows the Mudd Manuscript Library policy for preservation and access to audiovisual materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The original collection was a gift from David E. Lilienthal in 1965. Several additions to the collection were received over the next two decades, the last one for which documentation exists was in July 1987. Amendments to the original 1965 Deed of Gift allow access to previously restricted materials.
Appraisal
No information about appraisal is available for this collection>
Big business -- United States -- 20th century.; Chemical industries -- United States -- 20th century.; Dams -- Iran -- 20th century.; Dams -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Economic development projects -- Iran -- Khuzestan -- 20th century.; Economic development projects -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Flood control -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Flood dams and reservoirs -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Industries -- Power supply -- 20th century.; Mineral industries -- United States -- 20th century.; Natural resources -- Developing countries -- 20th century.; Nuclear energy -- United States.; Nuclear industry -- United States.; Nuclear nonproliferation.; Power resources -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Public utilities -- Wisconsin.; Railroads and state -- United States -- 20th century.; Regional planning -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Rural development -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Rural electrification -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; Water resources development -- Tennessee -- 20th century.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- United States.; Industries -- Power supply -- United States -- 20th century.; Khuzestan (Iran) -- Economic conditions -- 20th century.; Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950.; Audio tapes.; Autobiographies.; Correspondence.; Journals.; Manuscripts.; Memorabilia.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.; Lawyers -- United States -- 20th century.; Public officers -- United States -- 20th century.; American history/20th century; American politics and government; Cold War; Economic history; International organizations
- Series 1: Articles, books, and Lecture Notes by David E. Lilienthal, 1918-1952; 17 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1: Articles, books, and lecture notes includes articles and books written by Lilienthal from 1918-1949 and lecture notes from Lilienthal's time at law school.
  Arrangement
  The materials in this series are arranged in chronological order.
  - 1918, 1 box (Box 1)
  - 1922, 2 boxes
    - (1 of 2), 1922; 1 box (Box 1)
    - (2 of 2), 1922; 1 box (Box 2)
  - 1923-1926, 1 box (Box 3)
  - 1927-1933, 1 box (Box 4)
  - 1935-1943, 1 box (Box 5)
  - 1944, 6 boxes
    - (1 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 6)
      Includes: TVA - Democracy On The March, Harper & Brothers, 1944. [Filed in Boxes 6-11.1]
    - (2 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 7)
    - (3 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 8)
    - (4 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 9)
    - (5 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 10)
    - (6 of 6), 1944; 1 box (Box 11)
  - 1945-1946, 1 box (Box 12)
  - 1947-1948, 1 box (Box 13)
  - 1949, 1947-1952; 4 boxes
    - (1 of 3), 1949; 1 box (Box 14)
    - (2 of 3), 1949; 1 box (Box 15)
      Includes: This I Do Believe, Harper & Brothers, 1949. [Filed in Boxes 15-16.]
    - (3 of 3), 1949; 1 box (Box 16)
    - 1947-1952 articles in Collier's, New York Times, and New York Herald, 1 box (Box 150)
- Series 2: Speeches, 1918-1949; 30 boxes
  Series 2: Speeches consists of drafts and final versions of speeches given by Lilienthal.
  Speeches are arranged chronologically by year and month. Individual folders within each year are labeled with the location and/or organization where the speech was given, and possibly the title of the speech.
  - 1918-1933 March, 1 box (Box 17)
  - 1933 May-1934, 1 box (Box 18)
  - 1935 January-1936 June, 1 box (Box 19)
  - 1936 September-1939, 1 box (Box 20)
  - 1940 January-June, 1 box (Box 21)
  - 1940 August-December, 1 box (Box 22)
  - 1941 January-April, 1 box (Box 23)
  - 1941 May-December, 1 box (Box 24)
  - 1942 January-June, 1 box (Box 25)
  - 1942 July-December, 1 box (Box 26)
  - 1943-1944 June, 1 box (Box 27)
  - 1944 July-December, 1 box (Box 28)
  - (1 of 2), 1945; 1 box (Box 29)
  - (2 of 2), 1945-1946 June; 1 box (Box 30)
  - 1946 July-December, 1 box (Box 31)
  - 1947 January-August, 1 box (Box 32)
  - 1947 September-October, 1 box (Box 33)
  - 1947 November-December, 1 box (Box 34)
  - 1948 January-September, 1 box (Box 35)
  - 1948 October-December, 1 box (Box 36)
  - 1949 January - April, 1 box (Box 37)
  - 1949 May-December, 1 box (Box 38)
  - 1933 July 18 - 1935 October 24, 1 box (Box 39)
  - 1935 November 23, 1 box (Box 40)
  - 1937 November 5, 1 box (Box 40)
  - 1937 June 2-1940 April 3, 1 box (Box 41)
  - 1940 May 21 - 1940 December 3, 1 box (Box 42)
  - 1941 January 14, 1 box (Box 43)
  - 1941 November 14, 1 box (Box 43)
  - 1941 August 28 - 1942 December 20, 1 box (Box 44)
  - 1943 February 16, 1 box (Box 45)
  - 1945 December 10, 1 box (Box 45)
  - 1946 March 23 - 1948 November 30, 1 box (Box 46)
- Series 3: Correspondence and Related Materials, 1912-1949; 105 boxes; 2 items
  Series 3: Correspondence and Related Materials includes Lilienthal's correspondence to and from colleagues and professional contacts. There is some personal correspondence and in some cases reference to personal correspondence that is included in other series or subseries. Materials include correspondence about Lilienthal's publications and occassionally drafts of memoranda or speeches on particular subjects.
  The correspondence in this series is arranged first chronologically by year, and within each year alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - Subseries 3A: 1912-1929, 3 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal from 1912 to 1949.
    Correspondence is arranged first chronologically by year and within each year alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
    - Brandeis, Louis D.: Address, Brown University "Business - A Profession.", 1912; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1913; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Brandeis, Louis D.: Business - A Profession. Small Maynard & Company 1914, 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1917; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Carver, A.E. (Bert), 1917; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Jewish Welfare Board, 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Navy, United States; Auxiliary Reserve School, 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Simons, "Hi", 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Speech: ["Oration"] "The Mission of the Jew.", 1918; 1 box (Box 47)
      Includes Medal for Oratory.
    - Arvin, Newton, 1919; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Ehrman, Max, 1919; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1919; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Simons, "Hi", 1919; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Wabash College, 1919; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1920; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Eoch, Frederick H, 1920; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1920; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1921; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1921; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1921; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Longden, Henry.B., 1921; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Walsh, Frank P, 1921; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Frey, John P, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Walsh, Frark P, 1922; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Day & Day, Attorneys at Law, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Foster, William Z, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Green, William, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Grose, George R, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Lamb, Helen M, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Michaelson, Sam, and others vs. United States, Chicago, St. Paul, Minneapolis and Omaha Railway Company, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Nation, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1923; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Berle, Rudolph P, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Cadigan, John A, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Nation, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Szold, Robert, 1924; 1 box (Box 47)
    - Alexander, Raymond Pace, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Andrews, John B, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Nation, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Winnet, Nochem S, 1925; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Emmert, James A, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Frey, John P, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission: Valuation of Railroads, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Re Publication by David E. Lilienthal: "The Transportation Revolution.", 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Ripley, William Z, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Rosenbaum, Irwin S, 1926; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Commerce Clearing House, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Darrow, Clarence, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Rosenbaum, Irwin S, 1927; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1928; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Chicago Federation of Musicians, 1928; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1928; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1928; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Rosenbaum, Irwin S, 1928; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Berle, Adolf A., Jr, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Freund, Ernst, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Goldstein, Benjamin F, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Haight, George I, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Hot Springs Electric Light and Power Company - Case, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone Case, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Reed, Clyde M, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Public Utilities: Regulations, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Rosenbaum, Irwin S, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Watson, William R, 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
    - Wisland, H.M., 1929; 1 box (Box 49)
  - Subseries 3B: 1930-1931, 5 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal in 1930-1931.
    - Alexander, Raymond Pace, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Breckinridge, Frank P, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Burgets, Kenneth F, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - "Chicago Office" Material [Law Office of David E. Lilienthal], 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Cox, George Clarke, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Duls, William H, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Freund, Ernst, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Glaeser, Martin G, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Hogate, Kenneth C, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone Case, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Interstate Commerce Service, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Re La Follette, Philip F, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Lilienthal, Allen, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Re Longden, Henry B, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - MacLane, John F, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - National Association of Railroad and Utilities Commissioners, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Northwestern University, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Ransom, William L, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Raub, Joseph R, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Watson, William R, 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - Wisland, H.M., 1930; 1 box (Box 50)
    - American Bar Association: Public Utility Law Section - Meeting, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - American Bar Association, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
      Remarks by William L. Ransom At Dinner Tendered to David E. Lilienthal by Members of the Chicago Bar... On His Appointment to the Railroad Commission of Wisconsin, March 20, 1931.
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Banning, Kendall, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Bass, Basil N, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Becker, Samuel, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Benton, John E, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Berle, Rudolph P, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Beutel, O, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Bickley, John H, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Brandeis, Elizabeth, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Brandeis, Louis, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Breckinridge, Frank P, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Bruner, Henry P, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Burgess, Kenneth F, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Cassidy, R.B., 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - "Chicago Office" Material [Law Office of David E. Lilienthal], 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Cloon, William G, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Cooke, Morris L, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Cox, George Clarke, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Dickerman, Judson C, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Dinneen, William M, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Donovan, William J, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Eastman, Joseph B, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Emmert, James A, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Electric Distribution Costs, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Emison, John Rabb, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Evans, Evan H, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Evans, Harold, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Foreign Corporations, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Freund, Ernst, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Gardner, Addison L., Jr, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - George, Arthur T, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Glaeser, Martin G, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Glick, Philip M, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Goldberg, Lewis, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Grant, George R, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Guernsey, Nathaniel T, 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Guillou, A.V., 1931; 1 box (Box 51)
    - Haight, George I, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Hagenah, William J, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Hallgren, Mauritz, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Re Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Hugo, Colorado - Electric Light Plant Sale, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Jackson, WA, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Keedy, Charles C, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Kinspe, HA, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - La Follette, Philip F, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - La Follette, Robert M., Jr, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Landis, James M, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - League of Women Voters, Illinois, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
      Includes Address by David E. Lilienthal Concerning Public Utilities Regulation, February 3, 1931.
    - Lewin, John Henry, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Lilienthal, David E.: Testimonial Dinner Upon His Appointment To The Railroad Commission of Wisconsin Tendered By The American Bar Association Committee of the Chicago Bar, March 20, 1931, 1 box (Box 52)
    - Longden, Henry B.: DePauw University, Longden Day Celebration, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Loomis, O.S., 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - MacLane, John F, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Mack, Edwin S, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Maltbie, Milo R, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Miller, Paul D, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Milne, T. Baxter, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Mosher, William E, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Municipal Utilities, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
      Includes Address by David E. Lilienthal, "Some Problems of Municipally-Owned Utilities."
    - Murray, William H, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - National Association of Railroad and Utilities Commissioners, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Nelson, O.S., 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Nixon, Robert A, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Pearce, Thomas B, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Phleger, Herman, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Pinchot, Gifford, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Poss, Benjamin, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Price Levels, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
    - "Progressives" Conference, 1931; 1 box (Box 52)
      Includes Report of Committee on Public Utilities.
    - Public Ownership, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Public Utilities, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Public Utility Rates: Reductions, Structure, etc, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Public Utility Submetering, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Re publications By David E. Lilienthal, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - "Railroad File", 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Randolph, A. Philip, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Ransom, William L, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
      Includes Remarks At Dinner Tendered to David E. Lilienthal Upon His Appointment as a Member of the Railroad Commission of Wisconsin.
    - Raver, Paul J, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Reid, Frank A, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Reppy, Roy V, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Ripley, William Z, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Rosenbaum, Irwin S, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Rural Electrification, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Schlichting, Justus, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Seavey, Clyde L, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Severance Damages, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Shaughnessy, J~F, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Spurr, H.C., 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - State Statutes Concerning Public Utilities, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Staunton, F.J. Company Bond Issue, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Stearns, Albert J, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Stock, David, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - "Stories" File, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Van Wagoner, John D, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Vaughan, R.M., 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Walker, James B, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Walker, Paul A, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Walton, A.B., 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Watson, William R, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Wepman, Herman, 1931; 1 box (Box 53)
    - Wisconsin Power Districts Bill, 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisconsin Public Service Commission, 1931; 1 box
      - Accounting of Utilities, Depreciation, etc, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Electric Transmission Lines, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Milwaukee Electric Railway and Light Company, Street Railway Fares, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Mondovi Telephone Company Case, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Natural Gas, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Service Charge Case, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Street Railway Fares, Milwaukee Electric Railway and Light Company, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Trackless Trolley System, Kenosha, Wisconsin, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Teletype Writer File, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Union Cooperative Telephone Company Case, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
      - Wisconsin Telephone Company Case, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisconsin Public Utilities Legislation, 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisconsin Railroad Commission: Appointment of David E. Lilienthal, 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisconsin "Revisor's" Bill, 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisconsin State Utility Corporation Survey, 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
    - Wisland, H.M., 1931; 1 box (Box 54)
  - Subseries 3C: 1932-1933, 8 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal in 1931-1932.
    - Allen, Forrest, 1932; 1 box (Box 55)
    - Allen, Worth, 1932; 1 box (Box 55)
    - American Bar Association, Public Utilities Section, 1932; 1 box (Box 55)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1932; 1 box (Box 55)